# Konstantinos Kalaitzidis

Stockholm, Sweden

**८** SE: (+46) 72 444 5629

🛂 kon.kalaitzidis@gmail.com 🗹

ngithub.com/konkalaitzidis

Google Scholar 2

in LinkedIn 🗹

## Professional Summary

Graduate of Karolinska Institutet in Health Informatics with a background in Machine Learning and Computer Science. Motivated, and team-oriented with experience in Sweden, Ireland, the US, and Greece. Ex-TEDx Curator with a history of cross-disciplinary collaboration in fast-paced, multicultural settings. Completed mandatory military service.

## Education i

# Karolinska Institutet Joint Programme with Stockholm University

08/2021 - 06/2023

MMSc & MSc in Health Informatics 120 ECTS

Stockholm (Solna), Sweden

For syllabus, visit the programme website 2 | To access Thesis, visit this link 2

Thesis "Direct Behavior Prediction From Miniscope Calcium Imaging Using Convolutional Neural Networks"

30 ECTS | Grade: 36/40 | Supervisor: Professor Konstantinos Meletis

Activities Pfizer Skillbridge Case Competition Final, Elected Class Representative, TEDxKI Consultant

# University College Dublin (UCD) School of Computer Science

08/2018 - 03/2019

Exchange Studies (Erasmus) in Data Science 30 ECTS

Dublin, Ireland

Courses: Databases and Information Systems I, Data Mining, Designing and Developing Mobile Apps with Android

## **University of Thessaly (UTH)** Department of Digital Systems

09/2016- 07/2021

BASc in Computer Science and Engineering 240 ECTS

Larissa, Greece

Track: Software Engineering | For syllabus, visit the programme website 3 | To access Thesis, visit this link 5

Thesis "Perspectives & Use Cases of Quantum Computing" 30 ECTS | Grade: 10/10 | Supervisor: Dr. Ilias Savvas.

## Work Experience i

## Raider & IT Administrator Greek Army Special Forces

09/2023 - 06/2024

Mandatory Service

100%

Greece & Cyprus

#### Responsibilities

- Completed rigorous military training, earning the "Green Beret" distinction in a program with a 70% drop-out rate.
- Led IT administration tasks, including infrastructure optimization and automation of manual processes. Use of military intercoms and telemetry systems for monitoring military exercises and developments.
- Participated in national and joint allied exercises (NATO).
- Soft skills: discipline, resilience, initiative, adaptability, collaboration, attention to detail, clear communication

Tech Stack Windows Server (ADDS, ADUC, RDS, GPMC, DNS Manager), FlleZilla, Traceroute

Research & Master Thesis student 75%

Stockholm (Solna), Sweden

### Responsibilities

- Developed the Behaviour Prediction Neural Network (BPNN), a deep learning toolkit, to interpret animal behaviour during cognitive experiments
- Implemented and evaluated neural data analysis pipelines enhancing laboratory efficiency in post-experiment analysis.
- Awarded the 2022 Karolinska Institutet Foundation Scholarship for research contributions while a master's student.

Tech Stack TensorFlow/Keras, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Python, R, Git

# Data Intern Kry International AB

06/2022 - 08/2022

Kry Summer Internship Programme 100%

Stockholm, Sweden

## Responsibilities

- Admission rate < 5%
- Developed a user-friendly frontend for patient questionnaires, streamlining patient data collection for doctors.
- Collaborated within a cross-functional, agile team, contributing to project sprints and milestone tracking.

Tech Stack React, Java, AWS, Docker, Node.js, Git, Jira

#### Adviser Consulate General of Greece in New York

11/2020 - 05/2021

Internship Programme 100%

New York City, United States

#### Responsibilities

 Automated operational processes by implementing a digital tool that recognizes, organizes, and archives thousands of outgoing and incoming passport information leading to an overall productivity and performance increase of the Passports Department by 50%.

## Curator TEDxUTHLarissa

09/2019 - 09/2020

Lead Organizer & Licensee

100%

Larissa, Greece

### Responsibilities

- Led the organization and execution of the university's largest annual event, involving over 100 volunteers, 12 high-profile speakers, 100+ attendees, and support from 50+ sponsors and collaborators.
- Coordinated Directors responsible for handling different aspects of the event, such as finance, legal, marketing, experience, production and speaker relations. Oversaw all aspects of event planning and execution, including setting timelines and ensuring deadlines are met. Constant conflict-solving.
- Ensured strict compliance with TED and university guidelines, meticulously preparing and submitting required reports and documentation to both organizations, maintaining transparency and high standards throughout the event process.

## Competencies

Languages & Libraries: Python (Tensorflow/Keras, Scitkit-learn, OpenCV), R, JS (React), C/C++

Tools & Frameworks: AWS, Docker, Jira, JupyterLab, Git

Data Analysis: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Methodologies: Agile (Scrum)

Behavioural Competencies Ambition, Ownership, Communication, Teamwork, Problem-solving

## Honors & Awards

• Nova Member - an invitation-only network of the top 3% of professionals

Autumn 2022

• Karolinska Institutet Foundation Scholarship

Autumn 2022

• City of New York - Mayoral Service Recognition Program

Spring 2021

• Erasmus for Young Entrepreneurs grant to work in Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

Autumn 2019

• Third at the Greek National Racewalking Championship, 20KM Young Men

Spring 2017 & 2018

# Hobbies & Volunteering i

- Emergency Responder volunteer at the Hellenic Rescue Team of Attica.
- Long-distance running, skiing, hiking

## Referees I

- Panagiotis Papapetrou (panagiotis@dsv.su.se)
  Department of Computer and Systems Sciences, Stockholm University
- Konstantinos Meletis (dinos.meletis@ki.se)
  Department of Neuroscience, Karolinska Institute
- Nadia Davoody (nadia.davoody@ki.se)
  Department of Learning, Informatics, Management and Ethics, Karolinska Institute
- Ilias Savvas (isavvas@uth.gr)
  Department of Digital Systems, University of Thessaly